<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hello Welcome to my Portfolio on Vivien BOGNE</title>
    <link>https://vivien-dsa.github.io/Vivien_Portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hello Welcome to my Portfolio on Vivien BOGNE</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 11:00:59 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vivien-dsa.github.io/Vivien_Portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title> HR Analytics Job Change </title>
      <link>https://vivien-dsa.github.io/Vivien_Portfolio/post/project-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vivien-dsa.github.io/Vivien_Portfolio/post/project-6/</guid>
      <description>Problem statement: We are using the datasets named: &amp;ldquo;HR analytics: Data Science Job Change&amp;rdquo;. The Objective of the project is to :
Methodology. Data exploration : Data preparation : Features Engineering The Features The label. Results: The complete notebook is here:
References : 1. 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Face mask detector</title>
      <link>https://vivien-dsa.github.io/Vivien_Portfolio/post/project-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vivien-dsa.github.io/Vivien_Portfolio/post/project-5/</guid>
      <description>Problem statement: We are building here a face mask detector app. This is a project made for our knowledge. Indeed the objective is to:
 learn how to use open CV in order to load images, Use a DL algorithm in other to classifier images Use OpenCV to infer the classifier and display the results.  We will do this project using the steps below:
 Data collection and preparation: Collect or download some images and Prepare those images for a ML or DL algorithm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> AWS cloud computing </title>
      <link>https://vivien-dsa.github.io/Vivien_Portfolio/post/project-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vivien-dsa.github.io/Vivien_Portfolio/post/project-4/</guid>
      <description> Après avoir créer l&amp;rsquo;application de comptage de mot nous avons créer un corpus de 20 GB de mot en utilisant nltk. Ensuite nous avons crée un cluster EMR, chargé les données sur S3 et finalement définit une application SPARK dans notre cluster.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Create a model for Neural Machine Translation</title>
      <link>https://vivien-dsa.github.io/Vivien_Portfolio/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 11:15:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vivien-dsa.github.io/Vivien_Portfolio/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>Creating a translation system from a parallel corpus using OpenNMT which provides optimized tools to perform.
With OpenNMT we perform sub Tokenization, training, Translatation, Detokenization and then evaluation of our MT</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Recommender system</title>
      <link>https://vivien-dsa.github.io/Vivien_Portfolio/post/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vivien-dsa.github.io/Vivien_Portfolio/post/project-3/</guid>
      <description>Il s&amp;rsquo;agit d&amp;rsquo;utiliser le jeux de données MovieLens dataset afin de créer un système de recommendation. Nous créons un pipeline qui comprends : : Le chargement des données, la préparation des données, l&amp;rsquo;entrainement de modeles, une validation croisée et l&amp;rsquo;évaluation du modèles. Après avoir utilisé les modèles SVM, KNN: basé sur les utilisateurs et basé sur les éléments, nous effection un benchmarking. Il en ressort que le meilleur modèle est KNN: item based using the cosine bien que celui çi possède un temps d&amp;rsquo;entrainement beaucoup plus grand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Most Dangerous Country in EU</title>
      <link>https://vivien-dsa.github.io/Vivien_Portfolio/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vivien-dsa.github.io/Vivien_Portfolio/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>We are delighted to be able to inform the reader. is France the most dangerous Country in EU? We use crimes statistics from europea.eu website to explain or show the most dangerouns countries in European Union. We used 4 datasets, the Assaults, the number of intentional Homicide, the number of car thefts and one last with the number of the number of robbery. Using chloropleth maps, Tree map, bar chart in PLOTLY, we invalidated the null hypothesis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://vivien-dsa.github.io/Vivien_Portfolio/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vivien-dsa.github.io/Vivien_Portfolio/contact/</guid>
      <description>Vivien BOGNE TIENOUE Master of Science Computer Science:
Data Science and Analytics.
vivien.bogne-tienoue@epita.fr | +33 (0)7.53.31.91.97
bognetienoue@gmail.com | +33 (0)7.53.31.91.97
EPITA – Ecole d’Ingénieurs en Informatique</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
